Robbie Perlstein

robbie.perlstein@gmail.com | robbiep.com | github.com/robbiep

Summary

The journey from junior developer to engineering manager in less than 3 years at Shutterstock underscores my bias for action, my desire to grow my skills, my thirst for accomplishment.

Technical Skills

Regular Usage: Javascript/Node, Perl, Ruby, SQL, REST, SOA, Linux

Notable Usage: Puppet, Chef, Apache, Nginx, Java, C++, Python, HTML/CSS, Android

Experience

SHUTTERSTOCK Software Development Manager & Tech Lead

August 2016 - Present

- Provide technical leadership to a 6 person team in a rapid growth agile environment, developing full-stack vertically-integrated features and horizontal back end services.
- Technical owner of back-end services that directly support our team's product domain and satisfy POC, triage, and maintenance duties for multiple deprecated full-stack applications.
- Work closely with Product and Design to transform our vision into deliverable milestones, consistently communicating risk and uncertainty, and faithfully practicing radical candor.
- Conduct technical interviews, lead scrum ceremonies, helm stakeholder communications, drive initiatives supporting the organization, help with on call duties, and fight fires.

SHUTTERSTOCK Software Engineer

June 2014 - July 2016

- Designed and lead development of a RESTful API microservice in Node.js and MySQL.
- Planned, executed, and manage a large data and view migration a core feature set and associated data from a legacy monolith to an external service, using dual writes and an ETL.
- Took the lead developer role for a product that resulted in \$18 million annualized revenue helping to ideate the concept from product goal to actualized user experience, formulated
 the architecture, and orchestrated the development.

ZERISTA Ruby on Rails Developer

April 2013 – March 2014

- Customized a templated Ruby on Rails application by serving as a liaison to our clients.
- Created new widgets for the administrative CMS, proving clients with a WYSIWYG editor.

ENODIA FINANCIAL TECHNOLOGY

June 2012 – December 2012

Jr. Java Developer

• Developed real-time, server-side, FpML, financial transaction reporting software.

Education

B.S. Computer Science and Engineering, *Special Honors* University of Colorado, Denver

May 2014